A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Affirmative Action (N. Lee Cook), Series 8 FA357
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller gubernatorial records, Affirmative Action (N. Lee Cook), Series 8
1970-1971
Rockefeller Archive Center
New York (State). Governor (1959-1973: Rockefeller)
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
FA357
1.31 Cubic Feet 1 standard record storage box.
Biographical/Historical note
Nelson A. Rockefeller served as governor of New York from January 1, 1959, to December 18, 1973. He was the first person elected to four consecutive four-year terms as a state governor.
File Plan note
Former Classification: III 15 8
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Other Finding Aids note
Detailed finding aids for each series of this collection are available:
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Appointments Office (FA353)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Assembly and Senate Memos (FA354)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Joseph H. Boyd (FA355)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, James Cannon (FA356)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Counsel's Office (FA358)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York State Committee to Reelect the President (FA359)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Jerry A. Danzig (FA360)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Executive Chamber (FA361)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, 55th Street (FA362)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Issue Books (FA363)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Arthur Massolo (FA364)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Hugh Morrow (FA242)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York Office (FA365)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Civil Service Resolutions (Charles H. Palmer) (FA366)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Political Files (FA367)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Press Office (FA368)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Public Relations (FA369)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Departmental Reports (FA370)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, William J. Ronan (FA371)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Speeches (FA372)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Diane Van Wie (FA373)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Ann C. Whitman, Gubernatorial (FA374)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Gene Wyckoff (FA375)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York Republican State Fund Raising Reports (FA376)
Scope and Contents note
NOTE TO RESEARCHERS
This series contains a portion of the office files of N. Lee Cook, a member of Nelson A. Rockefeller's staff. They document official activities in the execution of his duties as a member of Nelson A. Rockefeller's staff. The actions, decisions, and exchanges of information or points of view documented here occurred in the course of proposing and implementing policies for the Rockefeller administration, political campaigns, and/or Rockefeller's personal activities. However, unless a document is specifically addressed to or from Rockefeller, or is referred to in a document addressed to him, it should not be assumed he saw the document or was aware of its existence or substance. Furthermore, researchers should bear in mind that staff files may contain documents or drafts addressed to Rockefeller that were never shown to him.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
This small series contains a portion of the files of N. Lee Cook, who served as a Program Assistant for Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller. These files are specifically related to Affirmative Action Programs. The majority of the files contain significant documentation of the Affirmative Action Program of Greater Buffalo (BAAP) and the work undertaken by that organization in 1970 and 1971. Primarily, these files deal with construction issues and equal employment opportunities, as well as affirmative action concerns on construction sites around New York State.
Latin America; International relations -- United States; New York (N.Y.); Legislation -- New York (State); Human rights; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1970; International relations; International economic relations; Arms control -- United States; Civil defense; Affirmative action programs -- New York (State); Arms control; Civil service -- New York (State); Economics; Civil defense -- United States; Civil service; New York (State); Political campaigns -- United States; Political science; Presidential campaigns -- United States; State governments -- United States; United States; Vice-Presidents -- United States; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1966; Presidential candidates -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Public policy; Public relations; Federal government -- United States; Government policy; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1958; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1962
- Affirmative Action Program (AAP) - Three Basic Plan (Buffalo, New York City, Long Island), 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  November 1970 copy of "Clarification and Specification of the Governor's Affirmative Action Program for Buffalo and Vicinity;" associated press releases and memoranda lifting construction moratorium in Buffalo after satisfying Equal Employment Opportunity issues; January 1971 Executive Order by NAR calling for Affirmative Action Training for Construction Projects in New York City.
- Affirmative Action - Coordination, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  April/May memoranda on Affirmative Action Programs in New York State, implementation and adherence to guidelines.
- Affirmative Action - Out of State - General, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Affirmative Action - Out of State - California, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Copy of "Affirmative Action Program in the Building and Construction Industry of California."
- Affirmative Action - Out of State - Chicago, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  "New York Times" article on problems with minority hiring in construction in Chicago area.
- Affirmative Action - Out of State - Human Interest Regarding Employment (HIRE) (Buffalo), 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Correspondence with Human Interest Regarding Employment (Buffalo Chapter) office on Affirmative Action problems in Buffalo area.
- Affirmative Action - Out of State - Illinois, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Copy of court judgement regarding Southern Illinois Builders Association v. Richard Ogilvie, Governor of Illinois. The judgement became known as the Madison/St. Clair Agreement and its implementation, the Ogilvie Plan.
- Affirmative Action - Out of State - Lebron, Roberto, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Correspondence with Lebron, a member of the Administrative Committee of the Board of Urban Affairs Fund of the New York Building and Construction Industry, on various legal and affirmative action issues.
- Affirmative Action - Out of State - Philadelphia, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Copy of Congressional Record wherein the "Philadelphia Plan" was read into the record.
- Albany Plan, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Correspondence on the "Pilot Program for Equal Employment Opportunity in Redevelopment Construction." an Affirmative Action program in the Capital District.
- Affirmative Action Program of Greater Buffalo (BAAP), 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Monthly accounts; correspondence and memoranda, clippings on Affirmative Action programs of Greater Buffalo, minutes of meetings, work of Buffalo Affirmative Action Task Force. Report.
- Affirmative Action Program of Greater Buffalo (BAAP), 1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Monthly accounts; correspondence and memoranda, clippings on Affirmative Action programs of Greater Buffalo, minutes of meetings, work of Buffalo Affirmative Action Task Force.
- Affirmative Action Program of Greater Buffalo (BAAP), January 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Affirmative Action Program of Greater Buffalo (BAAP), February 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Affirmative Action Program of Greater Buffalo (BAAP), March 1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Affirmative Action Program of Greater Buffalo (BAAP), April 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Affirmative Action Program of Greater Buffalo (BAAP), May 1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Affirmative Action Program of Greater Buffalo (BAAP), June 1971 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Affirmative Action Program of Greater Buffalo (BAAP), July 1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Affirmative Action Program of Greater Buffalo (BAAP), August 1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Affirmative Action Program of Greater Buffalo (BAAP), September 1971 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Affirmative Action Program of Greater Buffalo (BAAP), October 1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Affirmative Action Program of Greater Buffalo (BAAP), November 1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- BUILD Clips, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Clippings of articles on construction and affirmative action issues in the Buffalo area.
- Chemung County, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Proposal for Affirmative Action program in central New York State region.
- Cornell Labor School, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Proposal to hold a conference on Minority Employment at the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University.
- Department of Transportation - Bruckner Interchange, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Memoranda and correspondence concerning alleged Affirmative Action violations on the Bronx construction project.
- Department of Transportation - Jamestown, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Memoranda and correspondence concerning alleged Affirmative Action violations on the Appalachian Regional Development Act project in the Buffalo area.
- Domed Stadium, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Correspondence and memoranda on the building of a covered professional stadium in the Buffalo area.
- Governments, Agencies Conforming to March 2 Directive, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Letters and correspondence with various state agencies stating conformance with New York State Directive on Affirmative Action.
- Illinois, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Copy of court judgment regarding Southern Illinois Builders Association v. Richard Ogilvie, Governor of Illinois. The judgement became known as the Madison/St. Clair Agreement and its implementation, the Ogilvie Plan.
- Ithaca, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  Correspondence regarding training program in Ithaca-area trades.
- Long Island Plan, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Memoranda on minority employment in the construction industry in Long Island.
- Long Island Plan, Background, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  Correspondence regarding Affirmative Action adherence for State University at Stony Brook building construction.
- Mattina Correspondence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  Correspondence with Buffalo County Court Judge Joseph S. Mattina on Affirmative Action issues in the Buffalo area.
- Minority Coalition (BUILD), Buffalo Plan, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Correspondence and memoranda on the BUILD Affirmative Action Program in the Buffalo area. Reports on the progress of construction trade industry in implementing Affirmative Action.
- Niagara Falls, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  Memo to the Governor on possible suit by Niagara Falls construction company over building of Niagara Falls Convention Center.
- Nixon Administration - Poor and Minority Equal Employment Opportunity, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Correspondence and memoranda, reports and clippings on Nixon Administration efforts to correct problems in poor and minority hiring in the United States.
- Union Jurisdictions, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  List of the jurisdiction of construction trades in eight counties in the Buffalo area.